PAUL SPENCER

Software Engineer

+31 6 46 395 141

• Amsterdam, The Netherlands

► British and Irish (EU)

in linkedin.com/in/spencerpj

spencerpj.com

github.com/McFunshine

Summary

Software engineer with nearly three decades of delivering innovative solutions across fintech, energy, and govtech sectors. For the past half decade, focused on Java/Kotlin development and AI solutions. Completed a Master's in Software Engineering in 2022 while maintaining full-time employment. Currently architecting AI and emerging technology solutions while maintaining focus on practical business outcomes.

Experience

Khonraad Software Engineering

Lead AI and Emerging Technologies Architect

 $Amers foort, \ The \ Netherlands \\ Apr \ 2019-Present$

Technologies: Kotlin, Java, C#, Azure, OpenAI, Kotlin Multiplatform, JetBrains MPS, Python

- Updated software to comply with new laws within core Java product development team
- Responsible for complete development lifecycle of the innovation projects, including:
 - A full-featured iOS and Android App using Kotlin Multiplatform with OpenAI integration
 - OCR integration solutions
 - Domain-specific language extension for Decision Engine using JetBrains MPS

Captain McFunshines Software Engineering

Freelance Software Engineer

Soest, The Netherlands Aug 2019 - Present

Technologies: Kotlin, Azure, AWS, OpenAI, Kotlin Multiplatform, Python

- Developed Podmorph, an AI-powered solution for podcast and radio professionals
- Integrated multiple AI services (Anthropic, Google AI, OpenAI, Groq, Replit, Fal AI) deployed on AWS and Azure

Baker Hughes

Senior .Net Developer

Delft, The Netherlands Jan 2014 – Apr 2019

Technologies: C#, SQL Server

- Development and Product Evangelist of a subsurface modelling platform for the oil industry

Kempen & Co

Senior .Net Developer

Amsterdam, The Netherlands May 2007 – Dec 2013

Technologies: C#, K2, SQL Server, VBA

- Various internal projects to manage large portfolios and indexing products

Unisys

Developer

Schiphol Rijk, The Netherlands May 2001 – May 2007

Technologies: VBA, WebIntelligence, C#

- Responsible for developing reporting for world wide Accounts Receivables

ACT Financial Systems

London, UK

Developer Nov 1999 – Apr 2001

Technologies: PICK, Databasic, Universe, Visual Basic 6

- Responsible for developing and supporting a popular stockbroker settlement system

HSBC Investment Bank

London, UK

Developer Feb 1999 - Nov 1999

Technologies: PICK, Databasic, Universe

- Developed message processing, report writing, and screen handling programs

Lloyds Bank Stockbrokers

London, UK

Support / Business Analyst

May 1997 - Feb 1999

Technologies: PICK, Databasic, Universe, VBA, Visual Basic 4

- Support and Report Development for internal customers

Education

Universiteit van Amsterdam

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Masters Software Engineering

Graduated 2022

- Thesis: Projecting Rules: Improving Comprehension of Business Rules with Projectional Editing Making the Drools DSL Projectional with MPS
- Relevant Module: Software Evolution Used language workbenches to measure the evolution of a large Java codebase

Note: Completed while maintaining full-time employment

Wolverhampton University

BA European Business Administration

Hogeschool Holland

HEAO Joint European Business Administration

Wolverhampton, U.K. Graduated 1996 Amsterdam, The Netherlands Graduated 1996

Certifications

- $-\ 15$ Microsoft Certifications including 5 MCPDs in Windows, Web and Azure
- $-\,$ Nederlands Als Een Tweede Taal (NT2) Niveau 2

Languages

- **English:** Mother Tongue

- **Dutch:** Fluent spoken, listening and reading, intermediate written